RAZA HASAN

PRODUCT DEVELOPER



Dubai, UAE

L +971 508355270

☑ Raza.hasan289@gmail.com

https://Razadev.github.io

BIOGRAPHY

I am a proficient product developer with over six years of experience in Laravel, CodeIgniter, WordPress, and Drupal.

Throughout my career, I have successfully delivered a diverse range of projects spanning custom web applications, content management systems, and e-commerce platforms. My expertise lies in leveraging the strengths of each framework and CMS to create tailored solutions that meet the unique needs of clients. I also have experience in developing Android & Ios mobile application using Angular, and Ionic framework

EXPERIENCE

Sr Product Developer at Etisalat ESH / els (UAE) (Mar 2022 - Nov 2024)

Digital marketing agency based in Dubai.My role includes collaborate with stakeholders, project managers, and designers to understand project requirements and translate them into technical specifications.

Develop responsive and user-friendly application using Laravel and Drupal.

Software Developer at Evolve Wellness L.L.C. (Qatar) (Sep 2019-Feb 2022)

Develop and maintain the company's website to showcase its services, products, and offerings. Implement CMS to facilitate easy content updates and management by non-technical staff. Integrate e-commerce functionality into the website to facilitate online product sales, class bookings, membership subscriptions, and other transactions.

Associate PHP Developer at **Publicis.Sapient** (SapientRazorfish) (Mar 2017-Aug 2019)

Myrole includes customize and extend CMS platforms such as WordPress, Drupal, or Joomla to manage and publish digital content efficiently.Integrate web analytics tools such as Google Analytics or Adobe Analytics to track user engagement, website traffic, and advertising performance metrics.Develop and integrate APIs to connect with third-party platforms and services such as social media APIs, ad exchanges, and content syndication networks.

EXPERIENCE SUMMARY

- PHP Development
- Front-End Technologies
- Laravel Expertise
- CodeIgniter Mastery
- WordPress Proficiency
- Drupal Development
- Database Management
- Version Control
- Angular Ionic Framework
- Adaptable and Collaborative
- Problem Solver and Innovator
- Communication

TOOLS

- IDEs (Visual Studio Code / Sublime Text / Eclipse)
- Local Development Environments (XAMPP / WampServer)
- Microsoft Azure (Azure Cloud Migration / DevOps / IaaS and PaaS)
- Version Control Systems (Git / GitHub / GitLab)
- Package Managers (Composer / npm)
- Database Management Tools (phpMyAdmin / MySQL Workbench)
- API Development Tools (Postman)
- Security Tools (Burp Suite / Nikto / Nmap / SQLMap / Whatweb / WPScan / Wireshark)
- Performance Monitoring Tools (Google PageSpeed Insights)
- Project Management Tools (Jira / Asana / Slack)
- Android Studio

EDUCATION

Bachelor in Computer Science - 2013

Mumbai University - India

MY OBSESSIONS







Travel

Gaming

Adventures

WORKS-DESCRIPTION

REPs Qatar

The Register of Exercise Professionals (REPs) provides a system of regulation for passionate health and fitness instructors

Requirements

Technologies Used :-

- Backend Laravel (Framework)
- Frontend HTML5 Responsive, Ajax
- Integration Custom Api, Custom Helper Class, Validation Library, Database Structure And Optimization

DU-Bussiness Hub

DU Bussiness Hub Is Personalised And Mobile To Address The Needs Of Employees Who Are Accustomes To New Integrated Communication. This One-Stop-Shop Integrates Enterprise Corporate Services To Ensure That Employees Have A Single Solution For All Their Requirements

Technologies Used:-

- Backend Wordpress (CMS)
- Frontend HTML5 Responsive, Ajax
- Integration Custom Plugin, Social Share Plugin, Database Structure And Optimization

IVoucher

KWT iVoucher (Trade Program Kuwait) Is A Digital Technology Infrastructure To Support The Retailers To Participate In iVoucher, Earn, Redeem And Exchange The Points.

Technologies Used :-

- Backend Laravel (Framework)
- Frontend HTML5 Responsive, Ajax
- Integration Custom Api, Custom Helper Class, Import File With Validation, Excel Library, Pdf Library, Database Structure And Optimization

ALHarrif

Alharrif Is Mobile App For Digital Technology Infrastructure, To Support The Retailers, To Participate In Alharrif Earn, Redeem And Exchange The Points.

Technologies Used :-

- Backend Laravel (Framework)
- Frontend -AngularJs v1
- Integration Custom Api, Custom Helper Class, Import File With Validation, Excel Library, Pdf Library, Database Structure And Optimization

Etisalat Academy

UAE's largest single-source provider of total Telecom and Business Training and courses, Technical Training.

Technologies Used :-

- Backend Asp c#
- Frontend HTML5 Responsive, Ajax
- Integration Validation, database optimization, course booking

EisDigital

Digital Marketing agency expertise in Web Design, Web Development, SMS Solutions. **Technologies Used**:-

- Backend Laravel (Framework)
- Frontend HTML5 Responsive, Ajax
- Integration Custom Api, Email, Payment Gateway, Custom Helper Class, Validation Library, Database Structure And Optimization

OMB

Recruitment Agency in Dubai, OMB provides manpower staffing, recruitment, HR Solutions and Outsourcing services.

Technologies Used:-

- Backend Codeigniter (Framework)
- Frontend HTML5 Responsive, Ajax
- Integration Custom Api, Email, Custom Helper Class, Validation Library, Database Structure And Optimization

Connect.ae

Hyper local search engine to find companies, product and services.

Technologies Used :-

- Backend Drupal (CMS)
- Frontend HTML5 Responsive, Ajax
- Integration Custom Plugin, Social Share Plugin